# FARID MIRZAYEV

## COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT

+90 544 366 29 10 | mirzayevfarid@yahoo.com | Ankara, Turkey

# **ABOUT MF**

+

I am a 3rd year computer science student. I derive pleasure from following new technology trends. I am curious about discovering different software domains and have experience in mobile development, backend development, and machine learning.

# LINKS

+







# **EDUCATION**

+

# **Bilkent University**

- Ankara, Turkey
- Bachelor's Degree
- Computer Engineering
- Graduation date 2021

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java UML

C/C++ HTML-CSS

Javascript React

Flutter MySql

Android Firebase

Adobe XD Git/Github

# LANGUAGES

+

ENGLISH - Advanced

TURKISH - Advanced

RUSSIAN - Beginner

# **EXPERIENCES**

+

#### Radity

Oct 2019 - Jan 2020 | Zurich, Switzerland

- ▶ Worked on a project with 3K+ downloads
- ► Coordinated with 6 senior software engineers
- ▶ Developed a cross platform mobile app using Flutter, Firebase and Algolia
- ► Added a location sensitive language support to the app
- ▶ Fixed multiple bugs that were creating bottleneck for the project
- ► Took full lead of the project after 2 months of an introductory period
- ▶ Reported progress directly to senior management on a weekly basis

#### **Ultralab**

Feb 2019 - May 2019 | Ankara, Turkey

- ▶ Developed an android application using Java, Android and Firebase
- ► Teamed up with 6 software engineers
- ▶ Set up a system to handle data coming from a medical device
- ► Analyzed SDK to connect hardware and software via Bluetooth
- ▶ Created a data visualization system to deliver images representing data

## **Bilkent Mechanical Engineering Society**

Sep 2018 – May 2019 | Ankara, Turkey

- ► Worked within an engineering team of 12
- ► Led the software sub-team consisting of 5 people
- ► Incorporated an image processing software into a robot
- ▶ Used YOLO Deep Learning library to do real time object detection
- ▶ Facilitated communication between Arduino and Raspberry-Pi

## **Projects**

- ♦ Slay The Spire | Jan 2020 Ongoing
  - ► Developing a video game using Java and JavaFX
  - ► Using UML for visualizing the design of the game
  - ▶ Implementing object oriented concepts to build the game
- ♦ Done | Aug 2019 Sep 2019
  - ▶ Developed a cross platform to-do list app using Flutter
  - ► Configured a database system using Firebase and Firestore
  - ▶ Built a notification system for reminding tasks
- ♦ Callist | Sep 2018 Jan 2019
  - ▶ Developed a calendar app for desktop using Java, JavaFX and Jfoenix
  - ▶ Worked with a team of 5 people
  - ▶ Set up a MySql database system to store user's data